Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
I raped and abused Cristeta.
Captain Pedro Corpuz
and General Sergio Alfonso...
are sentenced by this
court to death.
Juanito!
Stand up!
The new officer-in-charge
of San Alfonso would be...
Governor Vicente Flores.
I lied.
Mr. Sergio never
abused me. It's not true.
You always go against
my word, Carmelita!
Destiny has already
changed its course.
We are not bad people.
Well,
don't let them roam around alone.
They might get into trouble.
Juanito?
Juanito!
Do not get angry, Father.
Maybe Carmelita just
needs more time to think.
That's why she went to Sugbu.
Time to think?
Getting married to you
is a no-brainer, Leandro.
You are a general.
Governor.
Do not worry.
Once Carmelita arrives,
I will make sure her wedding
with General Leandro will push through.
But, General Leandro...
I'm just wondering.
Are you and my daughter really in love?
There is no doubt.
What? I am to be married to Leandro?
Doña Soledad.
In love or not,
we all know you need this
engagement more than us.
To clean the reputation of your daughter.
After getting cheated by an Alfonso.
Juanito!
Can we just talk for a while?
Juanito, are you mad at me?
Why didn't you answer the
letters I gave to Eduardo?
Why didn't you show
up at our meeting place?
Why...
Because I don't want to
have anything to do with you.
Every time I see you,
I remember the betrayal
your father did to our family.
But...
But you told me,
when you're with me...
Everything gets better.
Just pretend that...
We haven't met at all.
Juanito...
Juanito! Juanito!
It's mother!
Carmelita...
Doña...
It is you.
I am grateful that
we were able to see each other
in my last moments...
Doña Juanita...
Mother, please don't talk that way.
Angelito...
Listen to your siblings.
Treat them as your second parents.
They'll be the ones to look after you.
As for you, Juanito.
Love your siblings.
You will be the ones
to give each other hope.
I love you very much, Mother.
Very much.
Mother? Mother!
Don Mariano, General Sergio,
and now…
Doña Juanita.
Everything changed
because I changed what was destined.
I can’t blame him
if he wants to completely
erase me from his life.
But still, I hope—
that our story is not yet over.
I don’t want to leave,
but this is the price
of my mission
in this time.
Because all of this…
is for Juanito.
Your beauty shines more
when you smile, Carmelita.
That is true.
I'm sure General Leandro will
love you truly and whole-heartedly.
So don't you worry.
And forget about Juanito.
If he really loved you,
he would not have let you go so easily.
And if he really loved you...
He would be here.
So please, Carmelita.
I hope you give Leandro a chance.
Every time I see you,
I remember the betrayal
your father did to our family.
Just pretend that...
We haven't met at all.
What was that?
Josefina, call the men!
No, wait.
Wait a minute.
Carmelita, are you out of your mind?
Juanito.
What's Juanito doing here?
I need to talk to Juanito.
But Carmelita, you could be seen.
Leandro and his family
are already on their way.
I'll do something about it.
Okay?
Alright.
Carmelita!
It'll be just for a moment!
I never thought that
we'd see each other again after
we bid our goodbye in Sugbu.
There's...
Something I wanted to...
Fix.
And get something back here.
And...
I'm hoping...
It's not too late.
What is it that you want back?
You.
Do you remember when we first met?
You told me I shouldn't
fall in love with you.
But I wasn't able to stop my feelings.
I want to you know that...
My heart only beats for you.
I thought if I turn away from you,
my heart and mind will soon forget you.
But it just made me long for you more.
And if you'll allow it...
I want to show you how
pure my intentions are.
Carmelita...
Yes, it's fine.
Does that mean...
You're letting me court you?
Yes.
Then,
- are you saying yes?
- Huh?
I thought you're just courting me?
You want to be official already?
I was just trying my luck.
Miss?
General Leandro and
Gobernadorcillo Flores have arrived.
Thank you.
Don't worry.
I'll tell Father that the
wedding with Leandro will not happen.
I was teasing Leandro actually.
I told him to...
Make sure he and Carmelita
would have lots of kids.
So that our families would
grow bigger and merrier.
Gosh! Here we go again
with the number of kids.
It's true that destiny
pulls two people in love closer together.
Leandro also told me
he and Carmelita have
been together for a long time.
Even before he became a soldier.
You and Leandro are
already in a relationship?
How can I explain that
I'm not really Carmelita?
I apologize.
My Father is naturally a joker.
Well, when would you like to get married?
All of us here are well aware that...
A lot has happened in the last few months.
I think it's better to let our
emotions settle down first.
Since Don Mariano and
his family were gone--
I mean, let's do the wedding in May.
If you still think that's too much time...
Maybe we can ask Mother Olivia's opinion.
No wedding shall happen
between Carmelita and Leandro.
And who are you to decide for our family?
What power do you hold
to choose our children's path?
I am here
to inform all of you...
That Carmelita decided to
be a servant of the church.
Carmelita,
you wish to also become a nun?
Yes.
I'm sorry I wasn't able to inform you.
But...
That is my decision.
But this engagement is...
Father!
Father.
We all know that your
decision is important.
But when I decided to serve
the church, you accepted it.
Father.
Please let Carmelita decide for herself.
Governor Flores.
I apologize for this incident.
Do not worry.
I will fix it.
Father!
Excuse me.
- Let go of me.
- Father!
Alejandro.
Alejandro!
Did your Father scold you?
I'm fine.
You?
How are you doing?
Would you believe me...
If I told you that...
My heart is deeply hurt right now.
I'm sorry.
I never wanted to hurt you.
My conscience is bothering me.
Leandro doesn't deserve all this hurt.
I can pretend to be
Carmelita on the outside,
but my heart cannot lie.
Don't say sorry.
Maybe you are just confused right now.
Because all the good times
you had with the Alfonsos are still fresh.
And that is why...
I will give you more time to think.
Carmelita.
I hope that...
you'd still choose me in the end.
I received a call from
the Governor-General.
He wants me to lead the battalion there.
To train them well.
I still don't know...
How long I will stay there.
But rest assured.
I will write to you everyday.
I hope...
That you respond to my letters.
Honestly,
I can feel that Leandro is a good person.
He always try to understand the situation.
The thing is, he loved the wrong person.
Did Juanito really go back to Sugbu?
Eduardo told me that
Angelito wrote to Juanito.
He said that Sonya suddenly bled,
and almost lost the baby.
So Juanito needed to return quickly
to take care of his sister.
He wasn't able to say goodbye.
Because he doesn't want to give Father
any more reason to get angry
Because he knows you'll escape again,
just to see him.
Carmelita...
I'm sure you'll see Juanito again soon.
You don't need to hide from us, Carmelita.
We are your sisters.
We know that Juanito is the reason
why you declined the marriage to Leandro.
And Mother Olivia is
helping you see him again.
The path you have chosen is not easy.
But don't worry.
We're here beside you.
We're here for the two of you.
Don't worry, Carmelita.
Thank you.
But I know Father and Mother
won't let me go back to Sugbu anymore.
Are you really sure
about your choice, dear?
About what?
About being a nun.
Is there any other reason why
you want to return to Sugbu?
Nothing.
I will explain everything to your Father.
Just make sure,
don't give Mother Olivia a hard time.
Mother, thank you. Thank you very much.
Carmelita,
take care of yourself.
And always remember
that we love you very much.
We're gonna do everything.
For you.
I wish for you eternal happiness.
It's so peaceful here.
Forgive me if...
I became angry at you.
Even though it wasn't your fault.
I promise...
It won't happen again.
By the way...
Mother Olivia has agreed...
For you to return to the convent tomorrow.
What are we doing here exactly?
This place...
is proof
that there is light beyond the darkness.
Have you heard of
the legend of the firefly?
Mmm. Before.
But...
I forgot about it.
Once upon a time,
there were secret lovers.
The daughter of the cabeza
and a humble fisherman.
But when their love affair was uncovered...
The young lady was taken away
by her parents.
According to legend,
the lady tried to go home on her own.
But she was never able to return.
She was never found.
One night...
A little light approached the fisherman.
It was his lost love.
Cursed by an engkanto.
After much pleading by the young man...
They were allowed to be reunited.
And together, they
became two little lights...
Bound to fly with one another.
Amidst the darkness.
Forevermore.
That story is quite sad.
Sad as it was...
The important thing was
they found each other.
And were reunited.
I will never forget this night.
The night
when the firefly found...
The woman he was dreaming of.
I won't forget this moment too.
The time when Juanito
and my heart became one.
For you.
This smells nice.
The sampaguita flower symbolizes...
Eternal love.
And...
And it came from...
the phrase "I promise you."
And I promise
that my love for you will never change.
Carmelita.
It's time to go.
Mother Olivia, may I talk to you for a bit?
Mother Olivia,
can I ask for a favor?
That you can join us for my birthday?
Dear child.
Haven't you finished embroidering?
It's almost night.
I'm done.
Ouch.
You know, dear...
You are quite adept at cooking.
You clean diligently.
And you can pray the rosary.
And do all the house chores.
But...
When it comes to embroidery,
it seems you cannot focus at all.
It's not a passion of mine, that's why.
Also, look at this.
My fingers are all bloody.
It's so painful.
Dear,
you heard about the Legend of the Rose
when you went to Binondo with Juanito.
I knew that Juanito asked
Mother Olivia to take me out.
But how did she know we watched
the play about the Legend of the Rose?
I never told her that.
I can hear your thoughts.
Oh my God!
Mother Olivia can read my thoughts?
Mother...
are you psychic?
Yes.
I can read your mind.
Why do you look so shocked?
Have you never thought
about my true identity?
Shocks!
Am I still talking to Mother Olivia?
Maybe she's possessed?!
Calm down, dear.
It is still me.
What if she hits me? My gosh!
I will not hurt you.
I don't hurt humans.
I do apologize
for not mentioning I can
read your thoughts before.
It's not just you.
Even the other people I encounter.
Mother Olivia is already in her 60s
but...
she's still beautiful.
She maybe prettier
during her younger years.
Thank you for the compliment.
Gosh!
I forgot she can read my mind!
Mother... what are you exactly?
Far from what you're expecting, dear.
But...
I'm not too different from you humans.
Like you,
I also have a mission to accomplish.
And a punishment I must pay.
What is the mission and
punishment you're talking about?
Something...
I must both fulfill.
My mission is just like a rose.
Beautiful and alluring.
But with it, comes thorns.
Able to bring forth...
Pain and suffering.
Someone has to sacrifice.
Blood must be shed.
For it to come to pass.
Sacrifice?
If I fulfill my mission,
Juanito's life would be spared.
Carmela...
Always remember.
This is not your fault.
No one is at fault.
It was Destiny who wrote
everything that has happened.
And will happen.
And the things that are happening now...
Is not the same
with Carmelita's time.
Father!
Father.
Have you heard of what
happened at the church?
I never imagined...
that Ka Tapang's forces
were already that large
here in San Alfonso.
Last week,
they stopped and attacked
a civil guard's carriage.
They even stole the weapons.
And now,
they protested in the middle of the mass.
Furthermore, they're condemning the death
of Don Mariano Alfonso.
Father...
It seems like...
they don't fear anyone anymore.
Did you catch any of them?
My men weren't able to identify the rebels.
After they dispersed
into the crowd at church.
The problem they bring
gets bigger and bigger.
We need to move.
I will postpone my travels to Cavite.
I will send out civil guards
to all public spaces.
Don't forget to add
security for Don Alejandro.
Especially since you're about
to be married to Carmelita.
You also need to gather
information about the rebels.
Who do you think...
would have the guts to
convince these people
to condemn the death of Mariano?
But...
The Alfonsos are exiled far away.
Make sure of that.
Very well.
Are you all ready to eat?
I'm so famished!
Mother Olivia,
thank you for fulfilling my wish.
This is a big gift to me already.
OMG!
October 21st is Juanito's birthday?
My dear friends.
I wish to introduce to you...
The woman who captured my heart.
Carmela.
If I say your real name,
you might get into trouble.
We are pleased
you could celebrate with us.
Let us all give cheers!
For the birthday of Juanito Cristobal!
Happy birthday, Juanito!
Eat!
Let's eat!
Go on, eat!
Have you heard of the story about
the handsome cat...
and the naughty rat?
One day, there was a handsome cat...
And he met
a naughty lady rat.
He wanted to eat this rat.
But since the cat was nice...
He didn't do it.
Until the days passed.
They fell in love with each other.
Even though they know
they shouldn't be together.
They still continued loving one another.
And they got married.
What's so funny about my story?
Because it's impossible!
A cat and a rat can't get married.
So you're saying it's
impossible for us to get married?
Juanito, all I'm saying is that...
I'm pertaining to the cat and rat.
Not us.
If that's so, then be with Leandro then.
To cap off my beloved brother
Juanito's birthday celebration...
Carmela wishes to sing a song for him.
This song is for you, Juanito.
I want you to know that
my heart only beats for you.
♫ It's harrowing to promise ♫
♫ that I won't think of you ♫
♫ Nothing will come true ♫
♫ even if we try again ♫
♫ Now, I confess ♫
♫ I can only be with you in my mind ♫
♫ Whenever I hear our song ♫
I never thought you'd sing a song for me.
Your heart gets easily grouchy.
You are hard to appease.
Does that mean you believe
that the cat and rat can get
married and live together?
Mm-mm!
I hope you promise
that the mouse will never
leave his beloved cat.
And that she will never come
and get married
to the other rat.
Yes.
I promise I won't leave
you and marry Leandro.
Carmelita!
A letter arrived for you.
It's from a man named Eduardo.
Why would Eduardo send me a letter?
Explain to me what's your
relationship to this man
and why he's writing to you?
Mother Ophelia,
I apologize but Eduardo
is my older brother.
I think, he wrote Miss
Carmelita's name on the envelope
in order for the letter
to be given priority.
Is this true, Mother Olivia?
You heard it right, Mother Ophelia.
Theresita and Eduardo are indeed siblings.
Miss, I think this is really yours.
Why would Eduardo send me a letter, though?
Miss Carmelita,
I know that I shouldn't
meddle in your family's affairs.
But because of your delayed
wedding to Heneral Leandro...
Don Alejandro has decided
to marry Maria into the Alfonso family.
Miss Carmelita,
I know you are also
against your Father's plan.
That is why I'm asking for your help.
Sincerely, Eduardo.
Mother Olivia.
I need to go back home.
Carmelita, dear!
Why didn't you inform us
you were coming home?
We could’ve fetched you from the pier.
Come and greet your father.
Who accompanied you here, Carmelita?
Father.
Is it true you are marrying
Maria off to Gobernadorcillo Flores?
Carmelita...
Don't start this.
You have just arrived
and you're already disrespecting me.
But Father.
Gobernadorcillo Flores
is too old for Maria.
They're the same age as Natasha!
Should I even listen
to a word she's saying?
I can't understand, but I've noticed
how you've changed so drastically!
When and where did you learn to disobey me?
Since you've been spending time with...
That woman.
You completely changed.
Carmelita is just saying the truth.
Alejandro...
Stop it.
Show respect to the Reverend Mother!
Don Alejandro.
It's not up to you to decide
the outcome of things.
Keep in mind that
your desire for wealth and power...
comes at a great price you wouldn't expect.
You have no right to speak to me that way.
From now on,
you are forbidden to be with that woman!
But Mother Olivia has
nothing to do with this!
The issue here is you insisting on
marrying Maria to Gobernadorcillo Flores!
Father!
I’ve run out of patience
with you, Carmelita.
You don't listen to me anymore.
I tried to understand you
since you were close to the Alfonsos,
that's why I didn't punish you.
But you went out of line this time!
Father!
Father, please.
Please try to understand Carmelita.
This child has to be punished!
Let her kneel on salt until I say
that she can return to her bedroom!
Alejandro...
Esmeralda!
What is it, sir?
Are you deaf?
Get the salt and tray!
Yes, sir.
Alejandro...
You don't have to hurt your child.
I will just talk to Carmelita.
She will never learn her lesson
if she won't taste punishment!
Alejandro!
Esmeralda,
I'm begging you.
Take pity on Carmelita.
Stop this, Father! Please have mercy!
Take your hands off me!
Didn't I tell you to kneel on salt?!
And you, Josefina!
You must learn to
discipline your sister!
Why would she be
taken to Laguna?
I think Father wants to
hide her far away.
Take that old man to prison!
I swear.
I will make you pay,
Alejandro!
Maria,
it's me.
How are you?
Carmelita, where is Eduardo?
What did Father do to Mang Raul?
Your eyes look sad.
Are you alright?
Carmelita,
I know you are aware that
since the beginning,
I have been charmed
by your doe eyes...
And sweet smiles.
Carmelita!
Juanito?
I'll take you away, Carmelita.
Let's elope somewhere
your Father wouldn't find.